# CHARLOTTE C. TAYLOR

charlotte.taylor7693@gmail.com • (732) 963-7444

charlottechalmer.me • github.com/charlottechalmer • linkedin.com/in/charlottetaylor7693

### **Executive Summary**

A web developer with hands-on experience and a passion for testing, building, and deploying fullstack web applications. A supportive team player and enthusiastic leader with exceptional interpersonal and problem solving skills and an aptitude for learning new material and technologies.

### **Expertise**

- HTML, CSS
- GIT / GitHub
- AJAX
- Mongoose / MongoDB
- Fast Learner

- JavaScript / jQuery Node.js / Express
- Angular2 •
- Communication Skills
- Team Player

## Relevant Experience -

## CodeCraft School of Technology

Boulder, CO

Software Apprentice

September - November 2016

An immersive JavaScript training program with over 700 hours of project-based full-stack web development

- Learned MEAN stack and other front-end and back-end development tools while creating projects individually and collaboratively.
- Designed and created fully-functioning and exceptionally creative projects from wireframe stage to deployment using agile principles, object-oriented programming, MVC framework, and functional programming.
- Developed a dynamic web application, Poll Arise, built on my passion for psychology. Developed the minimal viable product incorporating the MEAN stack, IBM Watson services, and Twitter API. Hosted by Heroku at www.pollarise.co.

Boulder, CO Brasserie Ten Ten

Server

February - May 2016

Named one of the best restaurants in Boulder, a fine-dining establishment that prides itself in customer service

- Ensured guest satisfaction by maintaining a professional and positive demeanor; highly knowledgeable of seasonal food and beverage menus.
- Maintained a high level of knowledge of beer brewing processes, and fermentation techniques, vintage, vintner and varietal of over 25 wines; knowledge tested by regular assessments.

**Urban Outfitters** Boulder, CO

Sales Associate

September 2015 - January 2016

A popular retail chain with a focus on younger generational trends in fashion, accessories, and quirky home-decor

- Assisted customers find products that fit their personal requests and needs.
- Provided excellent customer service at all times; handled quest conflict with tact to ensure an enjoyable shopping experience.

**ESPoused Events** Rumson, NJ

Intern

June - September 2015

A boutique event production and design house that offers customizable services tailor-fitted for client visions

- Attended to administrative duties: answered emails, placed event orders, and organized files, event photos, and client information; promoted events and managed social media
- Maintained a high level of knowledge of collateral trends by following social media sites
- Assisted in building a strong portfolio of venues and wholesale vendors e.g. Etsy
- Created informational event proposal kits for client use

#### Psychology Independent Research

Carlisle, PA

Research Assistant

January - May 2015

Upper-level independent research conducted for senior graduation requirement

- Organized literature review of over 45 articles and sources
- Transcribed 15 hours of interviews and analyzed transcriptions using qualitative and quantitative techniques
- Wrote and completed a 60-page APA-formatted research paper
- Presented findings at a student research conference

#### **Dickinson College Orientation Mentorship Program**

Carlisle, PA

First-Year Mentor

2014 - 2015

Selective mentorship program that provides transitional support to new college students throughout their first year

- Mentored 18 first year students; met bi-monthly with each student to ensure smooth transition
- Acted as a liaison between the student body and the administration

#### Pi Beta Phi Fraternity for Women

Carlisle, PA

Vice President of Event Planning

2013 - 2014

Officially elected vice-president responsible for alumnae relations and official event planning and coordinating

- Planned sisterhood, alumnae, and formal events for 250+ guests; selected vendors, negotiated contracts, and made payments frequently over \$1500
- Responsible for risk management; organized monthly workshops and educational seminars

#### WIRED | WIRED Café at Comic-Con

New York, NY | San Diego, CA

Intern | Intern

July 2014 | July 2013

Two internships focused on event planning at one of the largest comic conventions and administrative duties for major tech magazine, WIRED

- Researched over 30 Southern California start-ups to help grow WIRED Cafe at Comic-Con audience
- Oversaw the RSVP process for 3,000 WIRED Cafe at Comic-Con attendees
- Managed product shipment of 150 boxes from San Diego to the WIRED offices in New York City
- Attended to office administrative duties

#### **Career Artist Management**

Los Angeles, CA

Intern

July – August 2013

Major music management company that works with big names such as Maroon 5, A\$ap Rocky, Rick Springfield

- Managed social media presence; conducted research and produced social media reports for over 30 artists across 10 social media sites and number-reporting companies, e.g. Billboard
- Assisted agents with maintaining client information, media, and resume databases
- Improved the company's organizational and file-management systems

#### Relevant Projects -

Poll Arise: Using my interest in psychology, I built a site that takes in a user's Twitter handle and displays which politicians they are most and least similar to in terms of personality, needs, and values. Poll Arise uses the IBM Watson Personality Insights service and a natural language processor to analyze tweets retrieved through the Twitter API. Technologies used: Pug (Jade), HTML, CSS, JavaScript/jQuery, Node.js, Mongoose/MongoDB, IBM Watson, Twitter API, Angular2 templating. This website is hosted on Heroku. (2016) <a href="https://www.pollarise.co">www.pollarise.co</a>

Current: For a four-day hackathon, my team, named "Papaya Whip" after the web-safe color, developed an interactive productivity tracker that is based on the psychological concept of "flow". Current uses a timer similar to a pomodoro timer that prompts a user to take a break. The user is then prompted with a pre and post-break survey to retrieve data on many factors that mediate productivity as demonstrated through well-established psychology research. Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js and Mongoose/MongoDB. (2016) http://papayawhip.herokuapp.com/

#### Education -

**Full-Stack Web Development Professional**, CodeCraft School of Technology, Boulder, Colorado, 2016 **Bachelor of Psychology**, Dickinson College, Carlisle, Pennsylvania, 2015